<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>/share</title><link href="bockel.github.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="bockel.github.com/feeds/security.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>bockel.github.com/</id><updated>2012-10-26T12:25:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Third Party Security</title><link href="bockel.github.com/security/third-party-security.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-10-26T12:25:00-04:00</updated><author><name>William Heinbockel</name></author><id>tag:bockel.github.com,2012-10-26:security/third-party-security.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Many applications rely on externally developed code and libraries to
support certain functionality. Examples include the integration of
Apache or other webserver to provide browser-based configuration or the
use of parsing libraries such as &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;libxml&lt;/tt&gt; or &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;expat&lt;/tt&gt; to efficiently
handle&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;XML&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While use of these third party packages decrease development time and
produce better products, they do have a drawback &amp;#8212; your application
inherits the vulnerabilities and weaknesses of the third party&amp;nbsp;code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, there are two different ways to integrate third party code
into an application: &lt;strong&gt;embedded source&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;linked library&lt;/strong&gt;. Each
option has its own benefits, shortcomings, and customer&amp;nbsp;impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="34%" /&gt;
&lt;col width="19%" /&gt;
&lt;col width="19%" /&gt;
&lt;col width="28%" /&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;thead valign="bottom"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th class="head"&gt;Integration Type&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;Overhead&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;Security&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;Compatibility&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Embedded Source&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;worse&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;worse&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;better&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Linked Library&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;better&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;better&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;worse&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="embedded-source"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Embedded&amp;nbsp;Source&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!-- + flexibility (license dependent)
+ opportunity to apply fixes and test
- delays increase customer risk
- more tedious than linking --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One option involves the literal copying of the source code or
application libraries into the application distribution. That is, the
application and all of its third party dependencies are shipped as a
single, integrated&amp;nbsp;unit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Embedding the source with the application gives the developers some
flexibility to modify the existing code to better suit their needs
(license dependant). By having control over this integration, the
developers have time to throughly test any patches or other changes
before publishing&amp;nbsp;updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;object data="/static/images/third_party_security-embed.anim.svg" type="image/svg+xml"&gt;
Embedding Third Party Code&lt;/object&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the down side, managing embedded code is tedious. Developers are
responsible for tracking the third party applications for security and
other fixes that may affect their application. This is compounded by the
fact that some third party code do not make priority fixes clear, so
security fixes may be hidden within other functionality&amp;nbsp;updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, once a security fix occurs in a third party library, the
developers are responsible for applying that fix to their application.
Until they update the embedded code and publish an updated application,
all of their customers are at risk and vulnerable to the security&amp;nbsp;issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="linked-library"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Linked&amp;nbsp;Library&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!-- + not responsible for external code
+ automatically get patches (when platform is updated)
- no control
- updates may be incompatible, break app
- not user-friendly; dependency hell; requires package management --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other option for integrating third party code or libraries is to
build the application with links to the dependent libraries. By using
linked libraries instead of embedding them, the third party code is kept
external to the application. The linked library model is frequently used
by &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RHEL&lt;/span&gt; and can be seen in many open source&amp;nbsp;projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the dependencies are external, the responsibility for tracking and
maintaining that third party code shifts from the developer to the
platform maintainer. Unlike the embedded model, linking does not require
developers to push out application updates to handle patches in third
party&amp;nbsp;code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;object data="/static/images/third_party_security-link.anim.svg" type="image/svg+xml"&gt;
Linking Against Third Party Code&lt;/object&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One issue with using linked libraries is that the developers forfeit
control over the linked dependencies. They have no control over when or
how the linked libraries may be updated. Making sure that the
application is linked against the correct versions of the right
libraries (and all cascading dependencies are properly resolved) is a
difficult problem that is beyond the capability of most users. Tools
such as package managers are required to help determine all of the
dependencies and ensure the right libraries are&amp;nbsp;available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of security, having applications capable of sharing the same
linked libraries and having the update process managed externally should
yield improved security. However, in order to take full advantage of
these updates, an application must not be dependent on a specific
version of a third party library. By permitting this flexibility, the
application developers can benefit from updates by are taking a risk
that a future update to one of these linked libraries could break their
application. As there are no third party compatibility guarantees, an
update could change an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;API&lt;/span&gt; or modify the behavior of a utilized feature;
this would negatively impact the customer and necessitate an application&amp;nbsp;update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="swa"></category></entry><entry><title>Security Mentality</title><link href="bockel.github.com/security/security-mentality.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-10-23T11:51:00-04:00</updated><author><name>William Heinbockel</name></author><id>tag:bockel.github.com,2012-10-23:security/security-mentality.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;From the security perspective, we need developers and engineers to
&amp;#8220;think more securely&amp;#8221;. However, this is easier said than done. We need
to first address several important&amp;nbsp;issues:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What does &amp;#8220;think security&amp;#8221; mean and how does one use&amp;nbsp;it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can the concepts of &amp;#8220;think security&amp;#8221; be distilled and&amp;nbsp;taught?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="explaining-the-security-mentality"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Explaining the Security&amp;nbsp;Mentality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am only starting to examine the first&amp;nbsp;issue:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
What is it about the mindset of a security professional that
distinguishes them from developers and other professions?&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe a good place to start is looking at other methods of thought, such
as &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Critical_thinking"&gt;critical thinking&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Socratic_method"&gt;Socratic method&lt;/a&gt;. One well-known modern
teacher of thought, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edward_de_Bono"&gt;Edward de Bono&lt;/a&gt;, breaks the thought space into
three general types of&amp;nbsp;thinkers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Horizontal&amp;nbsp;Thinkers:&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Creative thinkers that focus more on abstract ideas and fantasy,
including artists and&amp;nbsp;designers&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Vertical&amp;nbsp;Thinkers&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Critical thinkers that use deductive reasoning to solve problems,
such as engineers and software&amp;nbsp;developers&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Lateral&amp;nbsp;Thinkers&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;&lt;span class="dquo"&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;Sideways thinkers&amp;#8221; who use more creative problem solving techniques
and are capable of freeing their thoughts from common thought biases
and&amp;nbsp;assumptions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;Lateral thinkers can be thought of as a combination of both
horizontal and vertical&amp;nbsp;thinkers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;object data="/static/images/lateral-thinking.svg" type="image/svg+xml"&gt;
Planes of Thought&lt;/object&gt;
&lt;p&gt;de Bono&amp;#8217;s portrayal of &lt;em&gt;lateral thinkers&lt;/em&gt; has many similarities to
common traits of security professionals &amp;#8212; they are capable of
approaching problems in innovative ways to find new security&amp;nbsp;weaknesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="lateral-thinking-puzzles"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Lateral Thinking&amp;nbsp;Puzzles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples of lateral thinking are best highlighted in lateral thinking,
or scenario, puzzles. In these puzzles, you are presented with a
situation and you must find a solution for under which circumstances the
situation can be reasonably&amp;nbsp;explained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trick to these puzzles is that there is no deducible solution to the
problem. That is, the solution cannot be reached using only the
information and assumptions based on the&amp;nbsp;puzzle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a common example of a lateral thinking&amp;nbsp;puzzle:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;A man walks into a bar and asks for a drink.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The bartender pulls out a gun and points it at him.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The man says, &amp;#8220;Thank you,&amp;#8221; and walks out.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the answer to this problem as well as other lateral thinking
puzzles, visit &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.rinkworks.com/brainfood/p/latreal1.shtml"&gt;Brain Food&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="schneier-s-law"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Schneier&amp;#8217;s&amp;nbsp;Law&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No discussion of the security mentality can be complete without a
mention of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Schneier%27s_law#Cryptography"&gt;Schneier&amp;#8217;s Law&lt;/a&gt;. While initially posed in relation to
cryptography, it is equally applicable to the general problem addressed
by the security&amp;nbsp;mentality:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any person can invent a security system so clever that he or she
can&amp;#8217;t imagine a way of breaking&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&amp;mdash;Schneier&amp;#8217;s Law (as coined by Cory&amp;nbsp;Doctorow)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advice is that security should be done in teams and made available
for peer review. This is because individuals are incapable of
considering every possible security threat; they are further constrained
by their assumptions and&amp;nbsp;biases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edward_de_Bono"&gt;Edward de Bono&lt;/a&gt; at least partially addresses this problem in what he
calls &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parallel_thinking"&gt;parallel thinking&lt;/a&gt;. Parallel thinking can be viewed as an
extension to lateral thinking where the thinking process is performed as
a group and focuses on exploring&amp;nbsp;possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step is to start exploring some of these common biases that
lead to vulnerabilities. My hope is that if we can understand &lt;strong&gt;why&lt;/strong&gt;
developers make security mistakes (besides pure negligence), we should
be able to adapt our approaches to software assurance and education to
minimize security&amp;nbsp;risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="swa"></category><category term="ia"></category><category term="assurance"></category></entry><entry><title>Security Assurance Stack</title><link href="bockel.github.com/security/security-assurance-stack.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-10-05T15:36:00-04:00</updated><author><name>William Heinbockel</name></author><id>tag:bockel.github.com,2012-10-05:security/security-assurance-stack.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There are many different &amp;#8220;assurance&amp;#8221; terms used to define various parts of the
network and information&amp;nbsp;stack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For most needs, terms like &amp;#8220;software assurance&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;information assurance&amp;#8221;
suffice. However, I cannot find any place that really compares the two other
than software assurance is one portion of the more general information&amp;nbsp;assurance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Information&amp;nbsp;Assurance&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;practice of assuring information and managing risks related to the use,
processing, storage, and transmission of information or data and the systems
and processes used for those purposes [&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Information_assurance"&gt;wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Software&amp;nbsp;Assurance&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;the level of confidence that software functions as intended and is free of
vulnerabilities, either intentionally or unintentionally designed or inserted
as part of the software [&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://acc.dau.mil/CommunityBrowser.aspx?id=25749"&gt;DoD&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a component stack, let us start with one like &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://venturebeat.com/2011/11/14/cloud-iaas-paas-saas/"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; used to compare
Infrastructure-as-a-Service (IaaS), Platform-as-a-Service (PaaS), and
Software-as-a-Service (SaaS) cloud&amp;nbsp;architectures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;object data="/static/images/component-stack.svg" type="image/svg+xml"&gt;
Component Stack Model&lt;/object&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, let&amp;#8217;s make some simple modifications: flip it over, split &lt;em&gt;application&lt;/em&gt;
into &lt;em&gt;software&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;services&lt;/em&gt; and ad the most important security element &amp;#8212;
&lt;em&gt;people&lt;/em&gt;. Then we can more specifically visualize the difference between
information and software (SwA)&amp;nbsp;assurance:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;object data="/static/images/swa-ia-stack.svg" type="image/svg+xml"&gt;
Software and Information Assurance Stack&lt;/object&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While software assurance is fairly specific, information assurance is much more
general and allows room for further&amp;nbsp;division.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To fill out the remainder of the stack between software and information
assurance, I propose the following terms and&amp;nbsp;concepts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Platform&amp;nbsp;Assurance&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;the confidence that the platform functions as intended and its capabilities
for managing risk and protecting the operating system platform, middleware,
runtime, software, and services from exploits. This include protections such
as stack protections and randomized memory&amp;nbsp;space.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Infrastructure&amp;nbsp;Assurance&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;the confidence that the infrastructure functions as intended and its
capabilities to mitigate risk and improve the security and reliability of the
operating platforms. This includes redundancy, failovers, and all hardware
protection&amp;nbsp;mechanisms.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;object data="/static/images/assurance-stack.svg" type="image/svg+xml"&gt;
Security Assurance Stack&lt;/object&gt;
</summary><category term="swa"></category><category term="ia"></category><category term="assurance"></category></entry></feed>