<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>/share</title><link href="bockel.github.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="bockel.github.com/feeds/standards.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>bockel.github.com/</id><updated>2012-10-08T16:15:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Agile Standards</title><link href="bockel.github.com/standards/agile-standards.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-10-08T16:15:00-04:00</updated><author><name>William Heinbockel</name></author><id>tag:bockel.github.com,2012-10-08:standards/agile-standards.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;With rapid development and deployment cycles, software developers cannot
wait on the long cycles needed for most standards bodies. In the case of
internationally recognized standards bodies such as &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IETF&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;W3C&lt;/span&gt;, and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISO&lt;/span&gt;,
the time need to take a standard from proposal to adoption is measured
in &lt;strong&gt;years&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With many high profile projects and Linux distributions relying on a
more agile, rolling release model, there is simply not the time to wait
on standards to be finalized to release updates to&amp;nbsp;customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the basis for a growing need for more agile standarization
frameworks that allow for organizations to rapidly innovate while still
recognizing the benefits of international&amp;nbsp;standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solution to this need will come from agile standards &amp;#8212; the
combination of open source software to rapidly develop and drive&amp;nbsp;standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="open-source-standards"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Open Source &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Standards&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The synthesis of open source with standards is obvious. Both rely
on open development models that require transparency and encourage
community&amp;nbsp;participation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his article, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blogs.adobe.com/open/impact-imminent-open-source-and-standards/"&gt;Impact Imminent: Open Source and Standards&lt;/a&gt;,
Adobe&amp;#8217;s Dave McAllister reaches a similar conclusion. He notes that the
development of many web standards including &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTML5&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSS&lt;/span&gt;, and ECMAscript
are all driven by open source&amp;nbsp;projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, open source does not a standard make. Based on my experience
with standards and standards organizations, there are several
recommendations for agile standard&amp;nbsp;development:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a class="reference internal" href="#identify-the-what-how-and-who"&gt;1. Identify the What, How and&amp;nbsp;Who&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Define the standard space. The more specific the more likely it is
you will&amp;nbsp;succeed&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a class="reference internal" href="#build-the-minimal-viable-framework"&gt;2. Build the Minimal Viable&amp;nbsp;Framework&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Focus on developing the minimal viable requirements for the&amp;nbsp;standard&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a class="reference internal" href="#open-source-the-development"&gt;3. Open Source the&amp;nbsp;Development&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Do the development in the open and under commercial-friendly&amp;nbsp;license&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a class="reference internal" href="#do-not-get-ahead-of-yourself"&gt;4. Do Not Get Ahead of&amp;nbsp;Yourself&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Do not allow yourself or the standard to get sidetracked too&amp;nbsp;early&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="identify-the-what-how-and-who"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1. Identify the What, How and&amp;nbsp;Who&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main goal for any standard must be adoption. In order to get
adoption, you must have a clear understanding of the &amp;#8220;what, how and
who&amp;#8221; for your&amp;nbsp;standard:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What&lt;/strong&gt; are you trying to&amp;nbsp;standardize?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How&lt;/strong&gt; will you standardize it and evaluate&amp;nbsp;compliance?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who&lt;/strong&gt; is the target community that will use the&amp;nbsp;standard?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When answering these questions, be as specific and constraining as
possible. The more restricted your answers, the more aware you are about
your potential adopters and the more likely you are to&amp;nbsp;succeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="build-the-minimal-viable-framework"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2. Build the Minimal Viable&amp;nbsp;Framework&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not get wrapped up in the details and possibilities. First flush out
the minimal set of requirements necessary for your standard to be
successful. In &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTML&lt;/span&gt;, this was the need for a communication protocol
(&lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTTP&lt;/span&gt;) and some markup language that could be rendered to the&amp;nbsp;user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This framework should be flexible enough to handle your problem space
but flexible enough to allow vendors to experiment with your standard
without breaking other&amp;nbsp;implementations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One example is &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSS&lt;/span&gt;. While &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSS&lt;/span&gt; defines the format of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSS&lt;/span&gt; rules and
provides some attributes, it still allows for vendors to implement their
own formatting extensions as long as the name begins with a &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;-&lt;/tt&gt;
hyphen. To allow for compatibility without breakage, when interpretting
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSS&lt;/span&gt; rules, implementations are permitted to ignore any attribute
starting with a &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;-&lt;/tt&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="open-source-the-development"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;3. Open Source the&amp;nbsp;Development&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open source all of your standard development. This not only allows for
potential users to see the code and how the standard might function, it
allows for people to start actively experimenting with implementation
options and provide&amp;nbsp;feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To allow for maximal user traction and allow for this standard
baselining code to be used in products, be sure to license the code
under a commercial-friendly open source license, such as &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0.html"&gt;Apache
License, Version 2.0&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="do-not-get-ahead-of-yourself"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4. Do Not Get Ahead of&amp;nbsp;Yourself&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not be afraid to say&amp;nbsp;&amp;#8220;no&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Focus on getting the foundation correct. Do not worry about what could
be done and never let the standard or community get distracted with
feature creep. If it is not covered by a &amp;#8220;what, how and who&amp;#8221; answer, it
is out of scope. Ignore suggestions and comments that do not help with
implementing the minimal viable implementation of the&amp;nbsp;standard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too many standards never become standards because they get bogged down
with being everything to everyone instead of meeting their initial needs
first; you will never be able to make everyone happy. Once you have a
standard, you can always add&amp;nbsp;features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know this one from first hand experience trying to get the log
standard &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://cee.mitre.org"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CEE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; off of the ground. There is too much focus on solving all
of the logging problems instead of first focusing on a standardized log
record format and implementation&amp;nbsp;thereof.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="agile"></category><category term="standards"></category></entry></feed>